[
    {
        "question": "What spell does Harry use to disarm Draco Malfoy in the Room of Requirement?",
        "answer": "Expelliarmus",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 31, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who teaches History of Magic at Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Professor Binns",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Hagrid introduce in his first Care of Magical Creatures lesson?",
        "answer": "Hippogriff",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 6, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the potion that grants good luck?",
        "answer": "Felix Felicis",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 9, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Quidditch position does Ron Weasley play for Gryffindor?",
        "answer": "Keeper",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 19, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Dumbledore bequeath to Hermione in his will?",
        "answer": "The Tales of Beedle the Bard",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 7, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first person to be sorted into a house in Harry's year?",
        "answer": "Hannah Abbott",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 7, Paragraph 9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Weasley family's owl?",
        "answer": "Errol",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 3, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What magical plant traps Harry, Ron, and Hermione in their first year?",
        "answer": "Devil's Snare",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 16, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who replaces Professor Trelawney as the Divination teacher?",
        "answer": "Firenze",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 27, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Voldemort's snake?",
        "answer": "Nagini",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 1, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What charm does Hermione use to make her parents forget her?",
        "answer": "Obliviate",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 6, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the pub in Hogsmeade where students often visit?",
        "answer": "The Three Broomsticks",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 10, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Harry use to breathe underwater during the Triwizard Tournament?",
        "answer": "Gillyweed",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 26, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the captain of the Gryffindor Quidditch team in Harry's first year?",
        "answer": "Oliver Wood",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 10, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Lupin teach the students to repel in Defense Against the Dark Arts?",
        "answer": "Boggart",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 7, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the mirror that shows one's deepest desires?",
        "answer": "Mirror of Erised",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 12, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who betrays Dumbledore's Army to Umbridge?",
        "answer": "Marietta Edgecombe",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 27, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What potion does Slughorn brew in his first class with Harry?",
        "answer": "Draught of Living Death",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 9, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the prison where Sirius Black was held?",
        "answer": "Azkaban",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 2, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature pulls the carriages to Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Thestrals",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 10, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the head of Slytherin house?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Hermione use to repair Harry's glasses in Diagon Alley?",
        "answer": "Oculus Reparo",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 4, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the goblin who helps Harry break into Gringotts?",
        "answer": "Griphook",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 26, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What position does Percy Weasley take at the Ministry of Magic?",
        "answer": "Junior Assistant to the Minister",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 4, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What magical creature does Hagrid keep in his hut in Harry's third year?",
        "answer": "Buckbeak",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 6, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Triwizard Tournament's first task creature?",
        "answer": "Dragon",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 20, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who becomes the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher in Harry's sixth year?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 8, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Harry use to summon his broom during the first task?",
        "answer": "Firebolt",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 20, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Dumbledore's phoenix?",
        "answer": "Fawkes",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 12, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the ghost of Ravenclaw house?",
        "answer": "The Grey Lady",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 31, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Harry use to defeat the Hungarian Horntail?",
        "answer": "Accio",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 20, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the house-elf who serves the Malfoy family?",
        "answer": "Dobby",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 2, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is revealed as the Half-Blood Prince?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 33, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Harry face in the maze during the third task?",
        "answer": "Sphinx",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 31, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Weasley twins' joke shop?",
        "answer": "Weasleys' Wizard Wheezes",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 6, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who kills Sirius Black in the Department of Mysteries?",
        "answer": "Bellatrix Lestrange",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 35, Paragraph 9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical map Harry inherits from the Weasley twins?",
        "answer": "Marauder's Map",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 10, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Harry use to save himself and Dudley from Dementors?",
        "answer": "Expecto Patronum",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 1, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the forest near Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Forbidden Forest",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 15, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the headmaster of Hogwarts before Dumbledore?",
        "answer": "Armando Dippet",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 13, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What magical object helps Harry find the Room of Requirement?",
        "answer": "Marauder's Map",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 18, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Death Eater who tortures Neville's parents?",
        "answer": "Bellatrix Lestrange",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 30, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What potion does Harry use to disguise himself as Goyle?",
        "answer": "Polyjuice Potion",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 12, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who teaches Potions in Harry's sixth year?",
        "answer": "Horace Slughorn",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 9, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Harry encounter in the Chamber of Secrets?",
        "answer": "Basilisk",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 16, Paragraph 9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that levitates objects?",
        "answer": "Wingardium Leviosa",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 10, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who becomes Minister for Magic after Fudge?",
        "answer": "Rufus Scrimgeour",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 1, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that repels water?",
        "answer": "Impervius",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 9, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who does Harry take to the Yule Ball?",
        "answer": "Parvati Patil",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 23, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of Hagrid's giant brother?",
        "answer": "Grawp",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 30, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Hermione use to free the dragon in Gringotts?",
        "answer": "Relashio",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 26, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Death Eater who impersonates Moody?",
        "answer": "Barty Crouch Jr.",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 35, Paragraph 9"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the caretaker of Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Argus Filch",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that creates a Patronus?",
        "answer": "Expecto Patronum",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 12, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Dumbledore use to detect magic at Privet Drive?",
        "answer": "Deluminator",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 1, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Gryffindor house ghost?",
        "answer": "Nearly Headless Nick",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 7, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the broomstick Harry receives in his third year?",
        "answer": "Firebolt",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 11, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who kills Dumbledore on the Astronomy Tower?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 27, Paragraph 9"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Hermione turn into after using Polyjuice Potion?",
        "answer": "Cat",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 12, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical tournament Harry enters in his fourth year?",
        "answer": "Triwizard Tournament",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 12, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first to be petrified by the Basilisk?",
        "answer": "Mrs. Norris",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 9, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Harry use to stun Umbridge's squad?",
        "answer": "Stupefy",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 32, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Hufflepuff house ghost?",
        "answer": "Fat Friar",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 7, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Harry fight in the lake during the second task?",
        "answer": "Grindylow",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 26, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who becomes Harry's Potions teacher in his first year?",
        "answer": "Severus Snape",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that conjures water?",
        "answer": "Aguamenti",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 21, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the head of Hufflepuff house?",
        "answer": "Pomona Sprout",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Harry use to destroy Hufflepuff's Cup?",
        "answer": "Basilisk Fang",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 31, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that locks doors?",
        "answer": "Colloportus",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 34, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the conductor of the Knight Bus?",
        "answer": "Stan Shunpike",
        "list of reference": "Book 3, Chapter 3, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that reveals hidden objects?",
        "answer": "Revelio",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 19, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who owns the wand shop in Diagon Alley?",
        "answer": "Ollivander",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 5, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the plant that shrieks when pulled from the ground?",
        "answer": "Mandrake",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 6, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the head of Ravenclaw house?",
        "answer": "Filius Flitwick",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Hermione use to confund the Slytherin Keeper?",
        "answer": "Confundo",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 14, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical hospital in London?",
        "answer": "St. Mungo's",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 22, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who replaces Hagrid as Care of Magical Creatures teacher?",
        "answer": "Professor Grubbly-Plank",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 15, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that silences noise?",
        "answer": "Silencio",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 19, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first Death Eater Harry encounters in the graveyard?",
        "answer": "Peter Pettigrew",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 32, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Hagrid breed illegally in his hut?",
        "answer": "Blast-Ended Skrewts",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 13, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that lights the tip of a wand?",
        "answer": "Lumos",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 15, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the matron of Hogwarts infirmary?",
        "answer": "Madam Pomfrey",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 17, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that unlocks doors?",
        "answer": "Alohomora",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 9, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who does Ron take to the Yule Ball?",
        "answer": "Padma Patil",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 23, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that banishes objects?",
        "answer": "Evanesco",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 13, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the Slytherin Quidditch captain in Harry's sixth year?",
        "answer": "Urquhart",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 14, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What object does Harry use to destroy the locket Horcrux?",
        "answer": "Sword of Gryffindor",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 19, Paragraph 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical newspaper?",
        "answer": "Daily Prophet",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 4, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who teaches Transfiguration at Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Minerva McGonagall",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 8, Paragraph 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that summons objects?",
        "answer": "Accio",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 20, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the ghost of Slytherin house?",
        "answer": "Bloody Baron",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 7, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that creates a shield?",
        "answer": "Protego",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 18, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the librarian at Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Madam Pince",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 11, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that repairs broken objects?",
        "answer": "Reparo",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 4, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the spell that causes objects to swell in size?",
        "answer": "Engorgio",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 13, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first student to be Sorted into Slytherin in Harry’s year?",
        "answer": "Draco Malfoy",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 7, Paragraph 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What creature does Harry encounter in the pipes of Hogwarts?",
        "answer": "Basilisk",
        "list of reference": "Book 2, Chapter 16, Paragraph 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the charm that amplifies the voice?",
        "answer": "Sonorus",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 18, Paragraph 5"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who replaces Sirius Black as Harry’s godfather figure after his death?",
        "answer": "Remus Lupin",
        "list of reference": "Book 6, Chapter 16, Paragraph 4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical creature that guards the Sorcerer’s Stone?",
        "answer": "Fluffy",
        "list of reference": "Book 1, Chapter 11, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "What spell does Dumbledore use to put out the lights in Privet Drive?",
        "answer": "Deluminator",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 1, Paragraph 2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who becomes the Gryffindor Quidditch captain after Oliver Wood?",
        "answer": "Angelina Johnson",
        "list of reference": "Book 5, Chapter 13, Paragraph 3"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the magical device used to replay memories?",
        "answer": "Pensieve",
        "list of reference": "Book 4, Chapter 30, Paragraph 6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the original owner of the Invisibility Cloak passed to Harry?",
        "answer": "Ignotus Peverell",
        "list of reference": "Book 7, Chapter 21, Paragraph 5"
    }
]